<?xml version="1.0"?>
<search count="2186" start-index="0">
  <results>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/04/itv-startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344144188">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>ITV abandons digital - great news for startups?</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> It&apos;s carnage at ITV, with confirmation - as MediaGuardian reported three weeks ago - of more than 500 further job cuts at the broadcaster. But what does this mean for innovation? By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>ITV abandons digital - great news for startups?</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-04T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="ITV" type="keyword" filter="/media/itv" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/itv" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/itv"/>
        <tag name="Regional &amp; local newspapers" type="keyword" filter="/media/local-newspapers" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/local-newspapers" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/local-newspapers"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Television" type="keyword" filter="/media/television" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/television" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/television"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> It&apos;s carnage at ITV, with confirmation - as MediaGuardian reported three weeks ago - of more than 500 further job cuts at the broadcaster.   Emily Bell&apos;s recent description of a &quot;sunset industry&quot; sums it up perfectly, but there are some surprising decisions in the inevitable cost-cutting that follows its 41% year-on-year drop in adjusted profits which mean an annual loss of £2.7bn for 2008: Faced with financial crisis, ITV has decided to try and raise £200m by scaling back what it sees as &apos;non-core businesses&apos; and, tellingly, that appears to include much of its digital portfolio.   ITV&apos;s big test... Photograph: leedsyorkshire/Flickr/Some rights reserved  Social networking site Friends Reunited, search directory Scoot and (probably) Freeview Multiplex A operator SDN are all to be sold. Gaming service ITV Play, shopping site Price Terrier and large parts of ITV&apos;s mobile division are to be closed. And ITV Local, the regional community and video service, is to be shut as a standalone business, but maybe some remnants will make it into the main ITV.com site which the broadcaster wants to prioritise as a streamed-video service.  With a share price already at a rock bottom 23.75p, ITV has been forced to take some drastic action. But ditching digital and abandoning investment in the most innovative parts of its business is extremely short sighted. If you think of a business as a family, these young digital businesses are the children that haven&apos;t yet achieved their full potential, and ITV has given up on them already.  On the plus side, ITV&apos;s withdrawal leaves a big opportunity for new players.  To pick one example: the local video space. Scaling back ITV Local comes soon after the BBC&apos;s regional video plans were vetoed. The early days of ITV Local were very impressive. No other traditional media company in the UK had attempted to explore local news sites and certainly not an ambitious network of them that combined professional news with user content, community and a rather neat integration with its local advertising network. It was logical for ITV to tap the existing regional news structure and the format was focused on local video way ahead of the competition - particularly in the sluggish local newspaper space.   With both the BBC and ITV out of any significant push in local video, and regional newspapers struggling with their cuts in jobs and resources as advertising continues to fall away, there surely this is now a space wide open for innovation and disruption?   Because decent news is very expensive and online audiences are not, largely, prepared to pay for it, this is an extremely tough business nut to crack. But there is demand, and there is the opportunity to build lightweight, responsive and, in terms of their infrastructure, cheap companies that fit and flex in this new space.   If ITV isn&apos;t there, it will be a whole lot easier. </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/03/research-researchfunding" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344062892">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>The world&apos;s innovation hubs, mapped out</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Visualisations are only as meaningful as the data that is used to compile them, and this innovation map comes with some weighty credentials. By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>The world&apos;s innovation hubs, mapped out</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-03T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Research funding" type="keyword" filter="/education/researchfunding" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/education/researchfunding" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/researchfunding"/>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="Research and development" type="keyword" filter="/technology/research" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/research" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/research"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> Visualisations are only as meaningful as the data that is used to compile them, and this innovation map comes with some weighty credentials.   Compiled by management consultancy McKinsey with the World Economic Forum, researchers used 700 variables including infrastructure, demand, government regulation, human capital and business environment to assess the activity and impact of hundreds of innovation hubs around the world.   The analysis picked out some fascinating trends. Firstly, political stability and the quality of transport and technical infrastructure have to be in place for any innovation hub to succeed. Secondly, hubs tend to develop a specialism and build credibility as an &apos;innovation hot spring&apos;, often around a small number of companies, before expanding.   Those hot springs are typically driven by either targeted, government-led investment projects, local benefits such as cheap labour and &apos;knowledge oases&apos; - places with a rich talent pool like an R&amp;amp;D department or research university. Further contributing factors are local regulation, local demand or the local investment scene but staffing remains key.   As well as the local talent pool, hubs need to be able to attract &apos;world-class talent&apos;. There are emerging problems in Japan and Europe, for example, because of an aging population, and in the US where highly specialised immigrants are starting to return home. For Asia, the challenge is training their growing populations to world-class level.   Survival during a downturn depends on diversification, according to the McKinsey analysis, which has identified three types of mature innovation cluster:   &quot;Dynamic oceans: large and vibrant innovation ecosystems with continuous creation and destruction of new businesses. Leading innovators and primary sectors change organically as the hub frequently reinvents itself through significant breakthrough innovations.  &quot;Silent lakes: slow-growing innovation ecosystems backed by a narrow range of very large established companies that operate in a handful of sectors. These clusters are frequently the source of a steady stream of &apos;evolutionary&apos; innovations and step-wise improvements.  &quot;Shrinking pools: innovation hubs that are unable to broaden their areas of activity or increase their lists of innovators and so find themselves slowly migrating down the value chain, as their narrow sector becomes less innovation driven and increasingly commoditised.&quot;  No surprise that Silicon Valley is a behemoth on this map, but delighted to see Bristol makes an appearance.    </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/03/startups-web20" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344078680">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Qype relaunches and redesigns as reviews hit one million</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Local reviews site Qype has redesigned to celebrate its one millionth consumer review this week. The site has something of a cult following in Edinburgh, Brighton, Oxford and London, but also has a huge following in Germany. By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>Qype relaunches and redesigns as reviews hit one million</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-03T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
        <tag name="Web 2.0" type="keyword" filter="/technology/web20" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/web20" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/web20"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> Local reviews site Qype has redesigned to celebrate its one millionth consumer review this week. The site has something of a cult following in Edinburgh, Brighton, Oxford and London, but is also one of the the most popular sites in Germany.   Qype claims more than 8 million unique users per month now, and though there&apos;s already competition from Trusted Places, Top Table, Fancy a Pint and Beer in the Evening in the UK alone, its biggest rival in Yelp, the US site that launched for the UK in January. Both the site and mobile app Qype Radar - which has notched up 55,000 iPhone and Android downloads so far - have been redesigned with better hyperlocal search, better navigation and a new, scratchy handwritten logo.   Qype&apos;s pitch is that it wants to provide depth as well as breadth in its reviews, but delving into its reviews reveal some real characters. Rose and Crown is a modest hairdresser in Covent Garden but has had to take on extra staff as a result of the popularity it has gained on the site. I Knit London has also been massively popular on the back of the Stitch &amp;amp; Bitch movement, and the delightful &apos;Meat Up&apos; group for the carnivorously inclined restaurant goer.  Qype has already had €11m in funding and its sites in Germany, France and the UK break even. Of its five language versions (Germany, France, Spain, Portugal and the UK), each country has hit a seam with very particular audiences; twenty-somethings in London, men over 40 in Germany and women in France. </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="audio" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/blog/audio/2009/mar/03/tech-weekly-podcast-law-startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344093498">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Tech Weekly: Legal advice for startup businesses</headline>
      <standfirst>Jemima Kiss puts your web startup questions to a legal expert in this week&apos;s Tech Weekly.  Also, the latest news, and an Elevator Pitch from Popjam.com</standfirst>
      <byline>Aleks Krotoski</byline>
      <section-name>Technology</section-name>
      <trail-text> Jemima Kiss puts your web startup questions to a legal expert in this week&apos;s Tech Weekly.  Also, the latest news, and an Elevator Pitch from Popjam.com </trail-text>
      <link-text>Tech Weekly podcast: Legal advice for startup businesses</link-text>
      <trail-image>http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2009/02/02/gavel140.jpg</trail-image>
      <publication-date>2009-03-03T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Aleks Krotoski" type="contributor" filter="/global/alekskrotoski" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/alekskrotoski" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/alekskrotoski"/>
        <tag name="Audio" type="content-type" filter="/global/audio" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/audio" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/audio"/>
        <tag name="Bobbie Johnson" type="contributor" filter="/global/bobbiejohnson" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/bobbiejohnson" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/bobbiejohnson"/>
        <tag name="Charles Arthur" type="contributor" filter="/global/charlesarthur" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/charlesarthur" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/charlesarthur"/>
        <tag name="Interviews" type="tone" filter="/global/interview" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/interview" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/interview"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Scott Cawley" type="contributor" filter="/global/scottcawley" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/scottcawley" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/scottcawley"/>
        <tag name="Vic Marks" type="contributor" filter="/global/vicmarks" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/vicmarks" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/vicmarks"/>
        <tag name="Victor Keegan" type="contributor" filter="/global/victorkeegan" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/victorkeegan" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/victorkeegan"/>
        <tag name="Facebook" type="keyword" filter="/media/facebook" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/facebook" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/facebook"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Yahoo" type="keyword" filter="/media/yahoo" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/yahoo" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/yahoo"/>
        <tag name="Technology blog" type="blog" filter="/technology/blog" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/blog" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/blog"/>
        <tag name="Facebook" type="keyword" filter="/technology/facebook" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/facebook" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/facebook"/>
        <tag name="Technology interviews" type="keyword" filter="/technology/interviews" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/interviews" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/interviews"/>
        <tag name="Law and technology" type="keyword" filter="/technology/law" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/law" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/law"/>
        <tag name="Pirate Bay" type="keyword" filter="/technology/pirate-bay" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/pirate-bay" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/pirate-bay"/>
        <tag name="Sony" type="keyword" filter="/technology/sony" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/sony" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/sony"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
        <tag name="Tech Weekly" type="series" filter="/technology/techweekly" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/techweekly" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/techweekly"/>
        <tag name="Yahoo" type="keyword" filter="/technology/yahoo" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/yahoo" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/yahoo"/>
        <tag name="Technology" type="keyword" filter="/technology" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="audio">
        <duration-minutes>31</duration-minutes>
        <duration-seconds>22</duration-seconds>
        <show-notes> Don&apos;t forget to...  • Comment below...• Call our Skype voicemail• Mail us at tech@guardian.co.uk• Get our Twitter feed for programme updates• Join our Facebook group• See our pics on Flickr/Post your tech pics </show-notes>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/03/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344105369">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>PDA&apos;s Newsbucket</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Our reading list for today. </trail-text>
      <link-text>PDA&apos;s Newsbucket</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-03T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="Newsbucket" type="series" filter="/media/newsbucket" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/newsbucket" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsbucket"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> ? Realtime Twitter search results on Google &amp;gt;&amp;gt; MT Hacks? Evan Williams predicts that &apos;normal people&apos; will use Twitter in five years &amp;gt;&amp;gt; TechCrunch? Flickr expands video uploading capabilities &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent? Fox debuts Italian web TV service &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Variety? White House says no to YouTube &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Mashable? Pentagon gets a blogger of its own &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Wired? FT deputy: &apos;Papers might start considering charging online&apos; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Press Gazette? Flock ditching Firefox, moving to Google Chrome &amp;gt;&amp;gt; TechCrunch? Banned in the Gates household - iPhones and iPods &amp;gt;&amp;gt; mocoNews? Microsoft confirms Live Search overhaul, but is it enough? &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent? Mobile phone use passes milestone as UN report reveals global growth &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? Write the Fake Digital Britain report - it might get used &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? What is Kumo, and will I want to use it? &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? Pirate Bay Day 11: Prosecution its their case, while the RIAA implodes &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? Colleges stumble on to the Twitter scene &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? Ofcom backs expansion of super-fast broadband &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian? Facebook users suffer viral surge &amp;gt;&amp;gt; BBC? Newspapers trying to figure out online business models &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Econsultancy? Twitter taking over DC&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Variety? iPhones and PCs take fitness to heart &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Reuters  Via delicious   </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/02/pirate-bay-p2p" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344031233">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Pirate Bay Day 10: Prosecution rests its case, while the RIAA implodes</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Very soon, the Pirate Bay vs Sweden trial will end, and the world&apos;s file-sharers can get back to work. Or get back to file sharing, at least. But for today, the prosecution is making its final attempt to pile on the pressure in its closing statements. By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>Pirate Bay Day 10: Prosecution its their case, while the RIAA implodes</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-02T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="Media law" type="keyword" filter="/media/medialaw" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/medialaw" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/medialaw"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="BitTorrent" type="keyword" filter="/technology/bittorrent" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/bittorrent" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/bittorrent"/>
        <tag name="Technology blog" type="blog" filter="/technology/blog" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/blog" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/blog"/>
        <tag name="Digital music and audio" type="keyword" filter="/technology/digital-music-and-audio" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/digital-music-and-audio" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/digital-music-and-audio"/>
        <tag name="File sharing" type="keyword" filter="/technology/file-sharing" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/file-sharing" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/file-sharing"/>
        <tag name="P2P" type="keyword" filter="/technology/p2p" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/p2p" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/p2p"/>
        <tag name="Piracy" type="keyword" filter="/technology/piracy" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/piracy" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/piracy"/>
        <tag name="Pirate Bay" type="keyword" filter="/technology/pirate-bay" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/pirate-bay" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/pirate-bay"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> Very soon, the Pirate Bay vs Sweden trial will end, and the world&apos;s file-sharers can get back to work. Or get back to file sharing, at least.  But for today, the prosecution is making its final attempt to pile on the pressure in its closing statements. Prosecutor Haakan Roswell pushed for a one-year prison sentence, telling the court: &quot;I believe that the correct punishment should be one year in prison and that is what I am requesting that the district court hand down in this case.&quot;  The thrust of their case is that those who run Pirate Bay have turned a blind eye to significant copyright infringement and must be punished for that, telling Swedish newspaper The Local that: &quot;&quot;A person who is holding someone&apos;s coat while they assault someone else is complicit in the crime.&quot;  Fellow prosecutor Monique Wadsted claimed that the site was built for piracy, given that it polices for child porn, incorrect file descriptions and corrupted torrents. Prosecution also claimed the site makes around $1m in profits each year, which brought guffaws from the co-defendants.   Apparently based on an estimate of the number of ad slots on Pirate Bay, the defense said there were no more than four spaces, rather than 64. &quot;It&apos;s totally absurd, those numbers are totally disconnected from reality,&quot; said co-defendant Gottfried Svartholm Warg. &quot;The old bastard&apos;s crazy.&quot;  As Ars Technica said, the case will come down to interpretation of the law. Tomorrow - the defence makes its closing arguments. Expect fireworks.  ? Meanwhile, the Record Industry Association of America is dealing with its own credit crunch, with initial reports claiming the body plans to make 30 staff redundant, including some in the anti-piracy department. A comment to Digital Music News said &quot;the music community is not immune from tough economic times&quot;.   Interestingly, Electronista credits the cuts to an increase in digital music revenues, which mean record labels are reducing the anti-piracy budget they give the RIAA - but they say the cuts could reach 100 staff worldwide. And their source claims the future of the RIAA - at least its anti-piracy initiatives - is a merger with the British Phonographic Industry and the International Federation of the Phonographic Industry - both based in London. </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/02/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344034769">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>PDA&apos;s Newsbucket</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Our reading list for today. </trail-text>
      <link-text>PDA&apos;s Newsbucket</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-02T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="Newsbucket" type="series" filter="/media/newsbucket" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/newsbucket" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsbucket"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> • Facebook users suffer viral surge &amp;gt;&amp;gt; BBC• Newspapers trying to figure out online business models &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Econsultancy• Twitter taking over DC&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Variety• iPhones and PCs take fitness to heart &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Reuters• Ad buyers warm to Spotify as it hits millionth-user mark &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent:UK• Andrew Keen: Real-time video is the future of the internet &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Independent• Google&apos;s &apos;it girl&apos; Marissa Mayer profiled in the The New Times &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Beet.TV• Democracy can&apos;t exist without newspapers &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Independent• Six ways to publish your own book &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Mashable• The internet is changing the game for celebrities &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Econsultancy• Rogue code led to Gmail shutdown &amp;gt;&amp;gt; FT• Information technology, 50 years ago &amp;gt;&amp;gt; TechCrunch• The cloud is the new dotcom &amp;gt;&amp;gt; TechCrunch• Earnings: FT profits from premium content as online subs kick in &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent:UK• Isle of Man considers Playlouder for its legal P2P music nirvana &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent:UK• &apos;Furious&apos; UK operators want Nokia to strip Skype from N97 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; paidContent:UK• Amazon caves to Authors Guild over Kindle&apos;s text-to-speech reading &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian• Blogging etiquette gets personal &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Guardian  Via delicious   </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/02/startups-digital-music-and-audio" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344035392">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Elevator Pitch: Pure Solo heralds a new generation of karaoke</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> Joining the highly competitive music startup scene, PureSolo has a genuinely new idea; a catalogue of 10,000 legal backing tracks to popular songs and software that lets players record their own voice or instrument over the top. By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>Elevator Pitch: Pure Solo heralds a new generation of karaoke</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-02T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="Elevator Pitch" type="series" filter="/media/elevatorpitch" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/elevatorpitch" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/elevatorpitch"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="Music and the internet" type="keyword" filter="/music/netmusic" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/music/netmusic" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/netmusic"/>
        <tag name="Digital music and audio" type="keyword" filter="/technology/digital-music-and-audio" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/digital-music-and-audio" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/digital-music-and-audio"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> Joining the highly competitive music startup scene, Pure Solo has a genuinely new idea; a catalogue of 10,000 legal backing tracks to popular songs and software that lets players record their own voice or instrument over the top. The recording software is free, and the site charges for various extra functionality, with downloads charged at between 99p and £4.99.  Pure Solo was today announced as a partner for the Arts Council Take Away scheme, which is designed to encourage more young people to start learning and playing instruments.  Pure Solo was founded in February 2007 with three directors, four full-timers and funded by a handful of private investors. Chief executive David Kaplan takes us through it.  • Explain your business to my Mum  &quot;Haven&apos;t you always wanted to hear your daughter sing or play an instrument over your favourite songs? Well, get her to download those songs from Puresolo.com and within minutes she can be emailing you her recorded versions for you to listen to at home, in the car or on her iPod. PureSolo has been developed to meet the needs of the music performer.&quot;  • How does that work?  &quot;The free software allows you to record yourself singing or playing over professional backing tracks with real musicians as accompaniment. The lyrics or music appear on screen and you can practice and record as many times as you like before adding reverb and saving as an MP3. What&apos;s really exciting is the ability to then share your recordings in the Pure Solo Community and post them to your Facebook page, burn your own CD or email the files to friends. The user can record against a downloaded track as many times as they wish.&quot;  • How do you make money?  &quot;We have a straightforward pay-per download model for the backing track and accompaniment and give the software away for free.&quot;  • What&apos;s your background?  &quot;I spent 22 years at Goldman Sachs in a number of trading businesses. That was a great environment to learn about business process, management, the importance of strategy and the need for connectivity to your client. Also, as a requirement in the music industry, Goldman Sachs was a terrific foundation for the respect of the legal elements of a business. While this has helped Pure Solo on a number of levels, the rest of our directors have a diverse skill sets and experience.  &quot;John Thirkell, our chief operating officer and co-founder, has 30 years in music as a renowned trumpeter with bands like Jamiroquai, Level 42 and Tina Turner. The chief technology officer Jonathan Knight is a former colleague of mine at Goldman, and our newest addition, Elyas Chowdhury, has 15 years in consumer marketing management for Nestle, Kraft Foods, and Expedia. We have titles but consider this a team effort and all our fingernails are equally dirty.&quot;  • How many users do you have now, and what&apos;s your target within 12 months?  &quot;Based on our current performance and distribution plans we expect to be achieving 100,000 unique users per month by the end of this year.&quot;  • Name your closest competitors  &quot;In the low-barrier-to-entry, recording-over-high-quality-backing-track space, we don&apos;t see a lot of competition. Naturally in the karaoke space it exists but we&apos;ve been called Karaoke 2.0 in Tech Digest and feel excited about that. In the education software market Sibelius and Finale are great products, although they serve a somewhat different user and purpose.&quot;  • How are personalisation and recommendation part of your business?  &quot;The core of our business is a personalised musical experience. Everyone loves to hear themselves play or sing - we take that a step further and make the process quick &amp;amp; easy and allow users to legally share the end results. The viral effect of this sharing should not only spread the word but also drive content requests and recommendations.&quot;  • And how do you plan to survive the financial crisis?  &quot;This is about personal discipline of living within your means. It always has been. During weak economic periods though it is important to think not only about survival but also pursue an equally disciplined investment and growth mindset. This applies both for personal and business purposes.  &quot;Despite being a new business and wanting to invest, survival will come from discipline on a day-to-day basis.&quot;  • What&apos;s your biggest challenge?  &quot;In the financial industry, especially trading, one had minute-by-minute updates as to how one was performing. In the building of a company the returns come over a longer period of time and that has been a major change.&quot;  • Which tech businesses or web thinkers are the ones to watch?  &quot;We really like the creative things YouTube can do in their next phase. We also believe Nokia is a great long-term mobile music strategic player. We also are fans of Spotify.&quot;  • What&apos;s the most important piece of software or web tool that you use each day?  &quot;We are pretty practical - emails, browsers, and search. But we do like the fun things too.&quot;  • Where do you want the company to be in five years?  &quot;We&apos;d love it if Pure Solo was being used as a core music teaching tool, not only throughout the UK but also around the world - and hope the individual music performer comes to think of us like they think of MySpace.&quot;  PureSolo.com  So what do you think?  • Pure Solo already has apps for the iPhone and Facebook, but do you think it would get more traction as a spin-off from another service?  • What advantage does Pure Solo have over PlayStation&apos;s SingStar community?  • And do you think the freemium model could be improved? Does it make sense to use an Apple-style free software download to try and sell music tracks?   </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2009/mar/02/facebook-socialnetworking" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344028662">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Facebook shrugs off warning to vet potentially malicious programs</headline>
      <standfirst>Social networking site&apos;s users under attack from programs seeking to steal personal data, says expert</standfirst>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Technology</section-name>
      <trail-text>Social networking site&apos;s users under attack from programs seeking to steal personal data, says expert</trail-text>
      <link-text>Facebook shrugs off warning to vet potentially malicious applications</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-02T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Social networking" type="keyword" filter="/media/socialnetworking" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/socialnetworking" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/socialnetworking"/>
        <tag name="Data and computer security" type="keyword" filter="/technology/data-computer-security" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/data-computer-security" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/data-computer-security"/>
        <tag name="Facebook" type="keyword" filter="/technology/facebook" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/facebook" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/facebook"/>
        <tag name="Internet" type="keyword" filter="/technology/internet" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/internet" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/internet"/>
        <tag name="Technology" type="keyword" filter="/technology" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> Facebook must revise its policy on letting programs that have not been previously vetted for malicious intent be unleashed on the site, a web security expert has warned.  But the founder of the five-year-old social networking site, Mark Zuckerberg, insists that he will not put such safeguards in place – arguing that &quot;an open system anyone can participate in is generally better.&quot;  Rik Ferguson, senior security advisor at Trend Micro said that in comparison to vetting procedures at rival social networking site MySpace and Apple&apos;s iPhone App Store for the iPhone, Facebook&apos;s hands-off policy – whereby anyone can offer a program for use by Facebook&apos;s 175 million users – will contribute to a growth in rogue applications, and that users should be wary of any new or fast-spreading ones they encounter.  Ferguson says he has monitored four malicious applications in the past week alone, as well as the resurgence of the &quot;Koobface&quot; virus, first seen last July, which sends out intriguing-sounding links to friends of an infected user, who is then tempted to a &quot;video&quot; page which instead infects their computer. Only PCs running Microsoft Windows are at risk.  &quot;The [Facebook] policy is facilitating the growth of rogue applications, and making it easier,&quot; Ferguson said. &quot;If Facebook does nothing, they will continue to increase.  &quot;This feels like a test run for something more malicious in the future. It may be about stealing identities, or it may be much more.&quot;  An application called &quot;Error Check System&quot; warns that friends are having problems accessing a user&apos;s profile, while two called &quot;Closing Down&quot; try to get users to install an application to prevent their profile being shut down for &quot;violating Facebook&apos;s terms of use&quot; – telling the target to visit a page to answer a charge that they broken the site&apos;s conditions of use.  The applications appear to be trying to gather personal information, but because Facebook hosts all user data and the data related to applications, it is impossible to tell how much information these rogue apps have gathered, said Ferguson.  It is possible that the information could contribute to identity theft by scraping contact details, siblings and pets&apos; names and maiden names, some of which can be to trick users into handing over passwords in sophisticated &quot;phishing&quot; scams.  &quot;The speed with which these applications have spread comes down to the classic combination of fear, uncertainty and doubt,&quot; said Ferguson. &quot;It&apos;s because these messages appear to come from friends that makes them so powerful.&quot;  Speaking to the BBC, Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg insisted that the site would not start vetting applications before they go live on the site.  &quot;Our philosophy is that having an open system anyone can participate in is generally better,&quot; he said. &quot;&quot;When we were starting this we wanted anyone to be able to develop an application. This has made it so students in their college dorm rooms could build applications for free. That&apos;s how I got started with Facebook. We really want to make sure that sort of innovation is possible.&quot;  A Facebook spokesman said the malicious applications and the more severe Koobface worm had affected only a small percentage of its users, and that it provided detailed advice on its security page.  Koobface last struck the site in December, posting comments on profiles which contain links that will download the virus to a user&apos;s PC, and also affected rival social networking sites MySpace, Bebo and Friendster.  Ferguson, meanwhile, advised users to regard every message on Facebook as &quot;guilty until proven innocent&quot;.  He said users should set their profiles to private rather than allowing them to be indexed by search engines, and advised that they remove phone numbers, family names and travel plans.  &quot;And just because a message seems to come from a friend, don&apos;t believe it. We give these messages more credibility because they come from someone we know but every message should be treated with caution.&quot; </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
    <content type="article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda/2009/mar/02/twitter-facebook" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/content/344003479">
      <publication>guardian.co.uk</publication>
      <headline>Facebook and Twitter: We couldn&apos;t agree on a takeover price</headline>
      <byline>Jemima Kiss</byline>
      <section-name>Media</section-name>
      <trail-text> So Facebook did indeed try to buy Twitter, we learn today. Investor Peter Thiel told Business Week the two sides could not agree on price or the structure of the company when they discussed a deal in the autumn. By Jemima Kiss </trail-text>
      <link-text>Facebook and Twitter: We couldn&apos;t agree on a takeover price</link-text>
      <publication-date>2009-03-02T00:00:00</publication-date>
      <tagged-with>
        <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article"/>
        <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost"/>
        <tag name="Jemima Kiss" type="contributor" filter="/global/jemimakiss" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/jemimakiss" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/jemimakiss"/>
        <tag name="Advertising" type="keyword" filter="/media/advertising" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/advertising" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/advertising"/>
        <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media"/>
        <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda"/>
        <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media"/>
        <tag name="Facebook" type="keyword" filter="/technology/facebook" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/facebook" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/facebook"/>
        <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups"/>
        <tag name="Twitter" type="keyword" filter="/technology/twitter" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/twitter" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/twitter"/>
      </tagged-with>
      <type-specific class="article">
        <body> So Facebook did indeed try to buy Twitter, we learn today. Investor Peter Thiel told Business Week the two sides could not agree on price or the structure of the company when they discussed a deal in the autumn.  Facebook did try to buy Twitter. Photograph: Jacob Bøtter/Flickr/Some rights reserved  That price issue was down to the value being paid in Facebook stock, and that meant agreeing on what Facebook was worth; Microsoft&apos;s proposal just over one year might have valued the firm at $15bn, but Facebook&apos;s own internal valuation was $3.7bn.  Thiel said: &quot;It became pretty clear it wasn&apos;t going to happen. The deal would have to be done with Facebook stock. And then you have to figure out how much the stock is worth.&quot;  The Twitter deal was reported at $500m. They also offered $100m in cash and the rest in stock - but based on Facebook&apos;s own valuation of $8-9bn. No wonder Twitter backed off. One source at Twitter said Facebook was obviously interested but &quot;didn&apos;t have much conviction&quot;.  Could it still happen? Thiel said he thinks Twitter is worth more than people think, and the company itself are adamant that it has a long way to go before it reaches its full potential. And the two still talk, though without any serious discussions.  And while Twitter&apos;s money-making potential has been under closer scrutiny, Facebook too is focused on &apos;improving its product&apos; rather than &apos;doing a MySpace&apos; and flooding the site with ads. If it did that, Thiel said, it could make as much as $1bn a year from advertising if it &quot;turned on all the dials&quot;. </body>
      </type-specific>
    </content>
  </results>
  <filters>
    <tag name="Media" type="keyword" filter="/media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media" count="2110" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media"/>
    <tag name="Article" type="content-type" filter="/global/article" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/article" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/article" count="2107" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/article"/>
    <tag name="Digital media" type="keyword" filter="/media/digital-media" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digital-media" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digital-media" count="1768" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/digital-media"/>
    <tag name="Blogposts" type="tone" filter="/global/blogpost" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/blogpost" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/blogpost" count="1636" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/blogpost"/>
    <tag name="PDA" type="blog" filter="/media/pda" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pda" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pda" count="1508" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/pda"/>
    <tag name="Technology" type="keyword" filter="/technology" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology" count="1112" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology"/>
    <tag name="Internet" type="keyword" filter="/technology/internet" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/internet" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/internet" count="641" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/internet"/>
    <tag name="Business" type="keyword" filter="/business" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/business" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business" count="278" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/business"/>
    <tag name="Internet startups" type="keyword" filter="/technology/startups" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/startups" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/startups" count="276" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/startups"/>
    <tag name="Newsbucket" type="series" filter="/media/newsbucket" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/newsbucket" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsbucket" count="265" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/newsbucket"/>
    <tag name="Newspapers &amp; magazines" type="keyword" filter="/media/pressandpublishing" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/pressandpublishing" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pressandpublishing" count="196" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/pressandpublishing"/>
    <tag name="Television" type="keyword" filter="/media/television" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/television" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/television" count="182" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/television"/>
    <tag name="News" type="tone" filter="/global/news" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/news" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/news" count="155" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/news"/>
    <tag name="Digital digest" type="series" filter="/media/digitaldigest" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/digitaldigest" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/digitaldigest" count="154" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/digitaldigest"/>
    <tag name="Social networking" type="keyword" filter="/media/socialnetworking" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/socialnetworking" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/socialnetworking" count="122" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/socialnetworking"/>
    <tag name="BBC" type="keyword" filter="/media/bbc" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/bbc" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/bbc" count="106" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/bbc"/>
    <tag name="Mobile phones" type="keyword" filter="/technology/mobilephones" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/mobilephones" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/mobilephones" count="99" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/mobilephones"/>
    <tag name="Blogging" type="keyword" filter="/technology/blogging" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/blogging" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/blogging" count="95" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/blogging"/>
    <tag name="Audio" type="content-type" filter="/global/audio" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/audio" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/audio" count="76" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/audio"/>
    <tag name="Web 2.0" type="keyword" filter="/media/web20" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/media/web20" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/web20" count="75" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/media/web20"/>
    <tag name="Web 2.0" type="keyword" filter="/technology/web20" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/web20" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/web20" count="64" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/web20"/>
    <tag name="Scott Cawley" type="contributor" filter="/global/scottcawley" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/scottcawley" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/scottcawley" count="63" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/scottcawley"/>
    <tag name="Twitter" type="keyword" filter="/technology/twitter" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/twitter" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/twitter" count="59" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/twitter"/>
    <tag name="Interviews" type="tone" filter="/global/interview" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/global/interview" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/interview" count="52" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/global/interview"/>
    <tag name="Technology interviews" type="keyword" filter="/technology/interviews" gdn-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?filter=/technology/interviews" web-url="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/interviews" count="51" filter-url="http://api.guardianapis.com/content/search?api_key=5ya7ejbsp8ymbjc6bdymeg8q&amp;filter=/global/jemimakiss&amp;filter=/technology/interviews"/>
  </filters>
</search>